[Music]
Hi, my name is Eusen, the developer
behind the new financial report
scheduling feature that's coming to
Business Central.
This feature will let you send financial
reports automatically on a recurring
schedule. And in this video, I'll be
giving a quick demo of how this works.
Let's start by going to financial
reports and have a look at the cash flow
report.
Under definitions, you'll find a new
schedules action.
This will take us to the new financial
report schedules page where you'll find
all that's required to start sending out
financial reports. Here
I have created a setup that will send
out the cash flow report on a monthly
basis.
Let's go through the basics
by selecting export to Excel and export
to PDF.
The report will be sent to my report
inbox in both of these formats.
By selecting send email as well, the
report will also be emailed to my
nominated recipients.
The next run date time field lets me
select when the report will be first
sent and the recurrence run date formula
will determine the cadence following
that.
Finally, I have selected myself as the
sole recipient of this report.
So what does this look like when the
report is sent?
This will be the email you receive.
I have received the report in both
formats which I have selected.
Back in business central I would have
also received the reports in my report
inbox
which we can find by using the logs
action.
Additionally, you can set up reporting
options and filters that are specific to
each schedule
using custom filters.
This will open the familiar report
request page. Here I will select a
different negative amount format for
this financial report schedule.
Similarly, if you want to select a date
filter that's different to the default
date filter on the financial report, you
can do so using the start and end date
filter formulas.
And that's all for this video. I hope
you go and give financial report
scheduling a try when it releases in the
near future.